rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>seetheway.xyz, AJQ's essays</title>
<link/>
<description>Writings about whatever comes to my mind.</description>
<item>
<title>The first step to freedom</title>
<link>freedom.html</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[ <h1>The first step toward freedom</h1> <nl> <p>There are two types of freedom that can be identified. Freedom from sin and freedom from God respectively. Libertarians fall into the trap of being free from "God" and rules of the universe and engaging in all manner of unnatural behavior or atleast promoting them, whereas believers or law-abiding-citizens are free from sin, but are bound to their God of Jesus or the Laws. </p> <p> Absolute freedom is not an ideal state you should strive for. Being free from both morals and laws will not lead you to the place you want to get to. I started with becoming free from sin first. If you go down this path you will suffer overcoming your vices, but will have your eyes opened. If you take the other path, and wish to be free from the state or God first, you are deluding yourself, by thinking that you sinful and unnatural moral guidance will lead you to a better place when free from God.</p> <p>This essentially means that your goal first should be to remove "sin" from your life. I have studied Christianity superficially, but don't follow the religion. I will henceforth use sin to describe activities that will degrade your perception of life or your overall life quality in the long run, while providing a seemingly great advantage in the short term. I don't deny the possibility that God exists, however I still can't sense its presence in my life and I don't worship it. I also don't believe in an afterlife right now. It is a possibility, but I will not live this one with the knowledge of there being a second regardless. When you sin you are degrading your own life first and foremost. Of course it might seem like you get away with it, but in the end it will always come back to bite you. Therefore I must lead a life with as little sin as possible. </p> <p>The first step I would take upon knowing this is identifying how I am sinning against myself, and consequently, how to stop doing it. Sin becomes a habit as it is pleasureable in the moment. These are called addictions. As an addict you will have a hard time identifying if you are addicted, as you are blinded by it. You may ask your peers, and that might work depending on the person, or they might overlook something crucial. Realise that a lot of these activities are actively normalised by the people spreading them for their own benefits and the addicts themselves, not wanting to face the reality of it. The good news is once you have overcome one of these activities you will have an easier time spotting a second one alike. They all follow the pattern described above of short term satisfaction, long term loss. I will now give you a couple of starting points to work off of. </p> <p>Common addictions: alcohol, smoking and other drugs, gambling, sex and masturbation, technology in general (gaming, social media) etc. </p> <p>If you engage in any of these activities habitually you are an addict. This is but a small sample of all of the possible addictions, but it should give you and idea of what to look for if you are clueless. </p> <p>Once you will have quit an addiction you eyes will open up. This will then make your pursuit of the Way easier. You can't see the way if you are blinded by sin, so take action for you own sake. I may write a guide to quitting some of these addictions eventually. </p> <nl> <nl> <p>AJQ, 2021. 12. 24.</p> ]]>
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Physical strenght is a precursor to mental strenght</title>
<link/>
<description>
<![CDATA[ <h1>Physical strenght is a precursor to mental strenght</h1><p>When it comes to personal development I used to have this idea that mental development trumps physical development in terms of its importance for me. This has changed completely.The reason I originally thought mental power was superior is just due to the mental demands on people today in their careers compared to the material. The difference between the pay of one that's "smart" or "clever" - whatever those mean - is ginormous, I thought. This was a very elementary thought indeed as you may realise, and for the record, no that wasn't what I thought in elementary school, it was something I developed later. Reality always seems to defy my expectations of it being predictable. First, I thought of it as black and white, good versus evil, then as black and white again, but the bad guys were lurking in the shadows as pupeteers controling every event secretly, and most people were unaware or in denial, only a selected few such as I could know of this truth. And of course they are from the same race aswell.Now you may see that the second world view is a bit more complex, but similarly foolish. I remained in this mindset for years to come. This gave me an excuse to fail at life and blame it on the elites or the illuminati, and be perfectly at ease with myself.</p><p>Similarly foolish is the idea of there being "smart" people and "fit" people. My observation may have been correct at the small vacuum of a social setting that was highschool. Teachers being smart and powerless or unwilling to stop any manner of bullying. Me being too "smart" to rise up and face the challenges of the deliquents, or even being "above violence". This wasn't my gut reaction to this, it was a defence mechanism of my mind, trying to rationalise my inaction in the face of the obvious call to action. That is to say, I lacked the courage to fight, and I "thought my way out of it" with excuses. I maintained the impression of being "smart" by getting decent enough grades and being butthurt about my peers not paying attention in class, a huge paradigm shift. This of course ended up taking me down the path of depression. My persona of being a goodboy student breaking down inevitably, as it was built upon lies and attempts to cope with reality. In the end I broke, but not in the way you might expect, I was moved to another class, and things settled into a better rythm. I was allowed to continue living with my lies and not to solve my issues...</p><p>Two years have passed since this, many things have hapenned. I ended up quitting my gaming addiction, my porn addiction, moving to a healthier diet, and exercising. My beliefs have been challenged truly. I have realised how futile it really is to try to be right and bring others down for not agreeing with my subjective truths. I realised the conceit of human "rationale", upon reflecting on my past decisions and my current ones, I have given up on being rational, I am not bitter about it in the slightest. I hope you will all have this discovery like me, the world would be a better place for it. I have begun to be actually interested in subjects and have gone on to see the beauty of learning.</p><nl><p><b>You are your mind, your mind is your whole body.</b></p><p>It's foolish to think that you can acheive anything in the material world without caring about your body itself. It is the vessel through which you experience the world. Now if you are indifferent about the physical, I can understand you wanting to disregard your body, however, your body is the lense through which your view everything. You can refute this if you think we are all part of a collective mind of the universe, but if you're along for this ride in the land of the material, why not try and see the effects exercise will have on your mind? If you are anything like me, thinking your way out of an issue of courage or fear, the worst thing you can do is think and justify yourself rationally. When you are violated, do think about whether you are right or wrong, but sometimes your brain will defy you to justify your inaction. Exercise trains you to confront pain and fear. These things while very simple to explain, are harder to tackle than the abstract problems you encounter when rationalising, hence why your brain chose the latter. All abstract thinking that comes from a place of weakness of heart, I have no use for anymore. I will rather be simple-minded, simple is the life of a man who is facing his fears head on... </p> ]]>
</description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
